<idea-plugin>
    <id>tools.dynamia.tasks</id>
    <name>Dynamia Tasks</name>
    <vendor email="hello@dynamia.tools" url="https://dynamia.tools">Dynamia Tools</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Dynamia Tasks is your developer task manager, living inside your IDE.
        Stop context-switching between browser tabs, issue trackers, and sticky notes.
        Dynamia Tasks brings all your tasks into a single, distraction-free panel
        right where you work — inside IntelliJ IDEA.</p>

        <h3>What it does</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Unified task list</b> — merges GitHub Issues, local task files, and any custom source into one clean checklist per project.</li>
            <li><b>Task Explorer</b> — browse, search, and cherry-pick tasks from any connector without leaving the IDE.</li>
            <li><b>Workspace checklist</b> — pin only the tasks you're working on now. Your personal sprint, per project.</li>
            <li><b>Open files from tasks</b> — jump directly to the relevant file mentioned in a task description with one click.</li>
            <li><b>Connector system</b> — plug in GitHub Issues out of the box, use local JSON task files, or connect any third-party tool with a custom connector.</li>
            <li><b>Labels and filtering</b> — keep things organised with labels, status filters, and grouping.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>GitHub Issues integration</h3>
        <p>
            Connect any public or private GitHub repository and manage its issues directly from IntelliJ IDEA.
            You can view, create, edit, comment, and close issues without ever opening a browser tab.
        </p>
        <p>
            To enable it, generate a <b>GitHub Personal Access Token (classic)</b> with the <code>repo</code> scope
            (or <code>public_repo</code> for public repositories only) at
            <a href="https://github.com/settings/tokens">github.com/settings/tokens</a>,
            then paste it in <b>Settings &rarr; Dynamia Tasks &rarr; GitHub Issues &rarr; Personal Access Token</b>.
            The token is stored locally on your machine and never sent to any external server.
        </p>

        <h3>Privacy-first, always</h3>
        <p>
            <b>No cloud. No telemetry. No accounts.</b><br/>
            Everything runs locally on your machine. Your tasks, your tokens, your data — 100% offline capable.
        </p>

        <h3>Get started in seconds</h3>
        <ol>
            <li>Open a project in IntelliJ IDEA.</li>
            <li>Click the <b>Dynamia Tasks</b> icon in the right tool window.</li>
            <li>Add local tasks instantly — no config needed.</li>
            <li>Optionally connect GitHub Issues: go to Settings, enter your Personal Access Token and repository (e.g. <code>owner/repo</code>).</li>
        </ol>

        <p><i>Built for developers who like their tools minimal, fast, and out of the way.</i></p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <h3>Version 1.0.3</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Improved IntelliJ startup flow to initialize Dynamia Tasks more reliably after project load.</li>
            <li>Enhanced embedded server lifecycle handling and project-to-server registry stability.</li>
            <li>General UX and performance refinements across the tool window integration.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <!-- Compatible with IntelliJ-based IDEs 2025.1+ (no upper bound) -->
    <idea-version since-build="251" until-build=""/>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">

        <!-- Tool Window anchored to the right -->
        <toolWindow
            id="DynamiaTasks"
            anchor="right"
            factoryClass="tools.dynamia.tasks.DynamiaTasksWindowFactory"
            icon="/icons/dynamia-task.svg"
            doNotActivateOnStart="true"
            stripeTitle="Dynamia Tasks"
        />

        <!-- Notification group for IDE callbacks -->
        <notificationGroup
            id="DynamiaTasks"
            displayType="BALLOON"
            isLogByDefault="true"
        />


        <!-- Modern startup hook (ProjectActivity replaces deprecated ProjectManagerListener) -->
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="tools.dynamia.tasks.DynamiaTasksStartupListener"
        />

    </extensions>


</idea-plugin>

